

Andrey Viazovskiy

Izmail, Odessa region (063) 773-86-97 gyglej.id@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrey-viazovskiy

I started my career working at the State Customs Service, where I acquired skills in organizing teamwork, developed analytical thinking and risk analysis. I really value professional qualities in my colleagues and expect sufficient professionalism and predictability from management.

Having completed a number of educational courses and training projects, I acquired knowledge and practiced skills in the field of front-end development and software testing. My experience includes using technologies such as Vanilla JavaScript, React, Next.js, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, software testing practices, and teamwork using Agile/Scrum methodology.

I have skills such as teamwork, the ability to set priorities, responsibility, attentiveness and perseverance, which are important for any development team.

With my knowledge, skills and desire for self-improvement, I will be a good addition to any development team, where I can apply my skills in front-end development and software testing, and contribute to the achievement of overall goals and the success of the project.

Unfortunately, I don't like to praise myself more than I actually am. So what follows are a few dry lines about my skills. Since the beginning of 2022 I have graduated several courses in the direction of Frontend development.

SKILLS

Knowledge and skills in Front-end:

- JavaScript (ES6+), React, NextJS 14, TypeScript
- HTML5, CSS3, Styled-Components, CSS Modules

Knowledge and skills in QA:

- QA methodologies: types of testing, approaches to testing
- Test design techniques
- Test documentation (test plan, test cases, checklists, bug reports)
- Practice with bug-tracking and test management systems

Soft skills:

Agile/Scrum methodology, teamwork, prioritization of goals, responsibility, attentiveness, persistence

Technical skills: HTML, CSS(SASS), JS/React, TypeScript, NextJS, Redux, Zustand, RTK Query, React Toolkit, React Router, Formik, React Hook Form, Material UI etc.

Tools: VS Code, Git, Figma, DevTools, Postman

Bug-tracking system: MantisBT, Jira

Test management system: Testlink, TestRail
Relational database management system: MySQL

EXPERIENCE

08.2006 - 08.2021

CUSTOMS OFFICER, STATE CUSTOMS SERVICE OF UKRAINE

I worked in various positions, incl. lead of the department. I have skills and experience in organizing the work of the team to achieve the goals, choose the means and the ways to resolve the issues.

I was responsible for monitoring the implementation of existing procedures, identifying and preventing risks that impact on their effectiveness

08.2022 - 09.2022

QA TEAMMATE, TEAM "TASQUE", BINARY STUDIO ACADEMY

It was learning project for 7 weeks (<u>Tasque</u>). The team of 7 developers and 3 QA should create the most complete and workable product. <u>Project Tasque</u>

MY RESPONSIBILITIES IN THE PROJECT: Manual testing, API testing (Postman), creating bug reports, project planning (describing the requirements by compiling user stories, creating project mind maps, use-case diagrams, clarifying requirements, making suggestions about UI/UX improvement, task management and other tasks), creating test documentation (test cases, check-lists, traceability matrix).

01.2024 - 04.2024

FRONTEND TEAMMATE, PROJECT FRESHHUB (online store), TEAM CHALLENGE

This training project started at the end of January 2024. A team of 3 developers, QA engineer, designer and project manager should create the most complete and workable product. Project FreshHub is an online fast food store that should have

responsive UI, customers can add and remove items from the shopping cart as well as create an order (required functionality: sorting by price; search by name; shopping cart and order creation)

FE PROJECT TOOLS: NextJs 14, ReactJs, Zustand, Material UI, SCSS, React Hook Form

MY RESPONSIBILITIES IN THE PROJECT: Creation responsive UI components from scratch, creating the structure and logic of interaction between the UI and the backend (using app router, server actions, API handlers), making suggestions about UI/UX improvement, documenting project-related information

03.2024 - present time

FRONTEND TEAMMATE, PROJECT "Wapm" (online store), TEAM CHALLENGE

This training project started in February 2024. I joined it in March 2024. A team of FE and BE developers, QA engineers, designers and project managers should create the most complete and workable product. Project "Шарм" will be a real online store with an adaptive interface, an administrative section and full customer support for creating orders.

FE PROJECT TOOLS: NextJs 14, ReactJs, Zustand, React DnD, GSAP, Next-Auth, SCSS, React Hook Form

MY RESPONSIBILITIES IN THE PROJECT: Creation responsive UI components from scratch, creating the structure and logic of interaction between the UI and the backend (using app router, server actions, API handlers), making suggestions about UI/UX improvement, documenting project-related information

04.2024 - present time

FRONTEND TEAMMATE, PROJECT "NA SELI U DIDUSYA" (booking rooms), <u>TEAM</u> CHALLENGE

This training project started in February 2024. I joined it in april 2024. A team of FE and BE developers, designer should create the most complete and workable product. Project "NA SELI U DIDUSYA" will be a real site for getting acquainted with the recreation center and booking rooms with an adaptive interface, an administrative section and full customer support for booking rooms.

FE PROJECT TOOLS: NextJs 14, ReactJs, GSAP, SCSS

MY RESPONSIBILITIES IN THE PROJECT: Creation responsive UI components from scratch, creating the structure and logic of interaction between the UI and the backend (using app router, server actions, API handlers), making suggestions about UI/UX improvement, documenting project-related information

EDUCATION

09.2001 - 06.2006

MASTER OF THE ACCOUNTING AND AUDIT, CUSTOMS ACADEMY OF UKRAINE

01.2022 - 04.2022

GRADUATE, COURSE "SOFTWARE TESTING", RIVNE CENTER OF VOCATIONAL EDUCATION OF THE STATE EMPLOYMENT SERVICE

The curriculum consisted of: QA and testing methodology, testing techniques, test documentation, testing domains: web applications, mobile applications and game testing; familiarization and practice with software for testers (Jira, MantisBT, Testlink, TestRail, Android Studio, Postman, Git, MySQL)

03.2022 - 04.2022

GRADUATE, COURSE "THE FUNDAMENTALS OF SOFTWARE TESTING",

QATESTLAB TRAINING CENTER

The curriculum consisted of: introduction to testing, web projects testing, approaches to the functional testing, software testing lifecycle, test design, test cases, mobile application testing, game testing

05.2022 - 06.2022

GRADUATE, COURSE "QA ENGINEER", G5 UNIVERSITY (G5 GAMES)

The curriculum consisted of: introduction to testing, basic software development models.

requirements testing, classification of types of testing, alternative classification of types of testing, bug life cycle, test design techniques, test documentation, mobile application testing, features of WEB application testing.

07.2022 - 09.2022

GRADUATE, "QA COURSE", BINARY STUDIO ACADEMY (BINARY STUDIO)

The curriculum consisted of: DOM/Browser API, Test Design techniques, Software Development Life Cycle, Requirements analysis, Postman, basics of HTML/CSS, API Testing, SQL.

10.2022 - 01.2023

GRADUATE, COMPLETE COURSE ON JAVASCRIPT + REACT - FROM SCRATCH TO RESULT, UDEMY

The curriculum consisted of: the basics of programming, algorithms and object-oriented programming, the basic concepts and principles of JavaScript, the study of AJAX, JSON technologies, the React library and absolutely everything related to it (including Redux), practice with Git and GitHub, creation full-fledged web applications.

02.2023 - 03.2023

GRADUATE, COURSE PRACTICAL JAVASCRIPT (ADVANCED LEVEL), UDEMY

The curriculum consisted of: practice on creating own JavaScript UI library, creating scripts in functional and OOP styles.

GRADUATE, LANDING THE LAYOUT AND CREATING THEMES ON CMS WORDPRESS, UDEMY

The curriculum consisted of: basic principles of working with content management systems (CMS), how to "pull" the layout on the WordPress content management system engine, how to create our own themes for WordPress, work with plugins for WP and with local servers, PHPMyAdmin; creation a full-fledged product for the customer, which he can customize as he wishes.

07.2023

GRADUATE, COURSE CREATING AN ADMIN PANEL WITH REACT.JS + PHP, UDEMY

The curriculum consisted of: creating an admin panel using PHP, React.js, axios, Gulp, Webpack. Practice with class components, authorization, work with backups.

11.2023

GRADUATE, THE COMPLETE COURSE ON MODERN TYPESCRIPT, UDEMY

The curriculum consisted of: static typing, interfaces and data types, classes and inheritance, asynchronous programming, generics, modular system, decorators.